Wonder by RJ palao part three summer you are beautiful no matter what they say words
can't bring you down you are beautiful in every single way yes words can't
bring you down Christina agilera beautiful weird kids SOME KIDS HAVE
actually come out and asked me why I hang out with “the freak” so much. These
are kids that don’t even know him well.
If they knew him, they wouldn’t call him that. “Because he’s a nice kid!” I always
answer. “And don’t call him that.” “You’re a saint, Summer zamina Chin said to me the
other day. “I couldn’t do what you’re
doing.” “It’s not a big deal,” I answered her truthfully. “Did Mr. Tushman ask you to be
friends with him?” Charlotte Cody asked. “No.
I’m friends with him because I want to be friends with him,” I answered. Who knew
that my sitting with August Pullman at lunch would be such a big deal? People
acted like it was the strangest thing in the world. It’s weird how weird kids can
be. I sat with him that first day because
I felt sorry for him. That’s all. Here he was, this Strang looking kid in a brand
new school.
No one was talking to him. Everyone was staring at him. All the girls at my table
were whispering about him. He wasn’t the only new kid at Beacher Prep, but he was
the only one everyone was talking about.
Julian had nicknamed him the Zombie Kid, and that’s what everyone was calling him.
“Did you see the Zombie Kid yet?” Stuff like that gets around fast. And August
knew it. It’s hard enough being the new kid even when you have a normal face.
Imagine having his face? So I just went over and sat with him. Not a biggie. I
wish people would stop trying to turn it into something major. He’s just a kid. The
weirdest looking kid I’ve ever seen, yes.
But just a kid the plague I DO ADMIT August’s face
takes him getting used to. I’ve been sitting with him for 2 weeks now, and
let’s just say he not the neatest eater in the world. But other than that, he’s
pretty nice. I should also say that I don’t really feel sorry for him anymore.
That might have been what made me sit down with him the first time, but it’s
not why I keep sitting down with him. I keep sitting down with him because he is
fun. One of the things I’m not loving
about this year is how a lot of the kids
are acting like they’re too grown up to play things anymore. All they want to do
is “hang out” and “talk talk at recess. And all they talk about is who likes who and
who is cute and isn’t cute. August doesn’t bother about that stuff. He likes
to play Four Square recess, which I love to play, too. It was actually because I
was playing Four Square with August that I found out about the Plague. Apparently
this is a “game” that’s been going on since the beginning of the year. Anyone
who accidentally touches August has only 30 seconds to wash their hands or find
hand sanitizer before they catch the Plague. I’m not sure what happens if you
actually catch the Plague because nobody’s touched August yet— —not directly.
How I found out about this is that Maya marwitz told me that the reason she
won’t play Four Square with us at recess is that she doesn’t want to catch the
Plague. I was like, “What’s the Plague?” And she told me. I told Maya I thought that
was really dumb and she agreed, but she still wouldn’t touch a ball that August
just touched, not if she could help it the Halloween party I WAS REALLY
excited because I got an invitation to Savannah's Halloween party Savannah is
probably the most popular girl in the school. All the boys like her. All the
girls want to be friends with her. She was the first girl in the grade to
actually have a “boyfriend.” It was some kid who goes to MS 281 oh she dumped him
and started dating Henry Joplin, which makes sense because the two of them
totally look like teenagers already. Anyway, even though I’m not in
the “popular” group, I somehow got invited, which is very cool. When I told Savannah
I got her invitation and we' be going to her party, she was really nice to me
although she made sure to tell me that she didn’t invite a lot of people, so I
shouldn’t go around bragging to everyone that I got invited. Maya didn’t get in
invited, for instance Savannah also made sure to tell me not to wear a costume.
It’s good she told me because, of course, I would have worn a costume to a
Halloween party— —not the unicorn costume I made for the Halloween Parade, but the
Goth girl get up that I’d worn to school.
But even that was a no no for Savannah's party. The only negative about my going
to Savannah's party was that now I wouldn’t be able to go to the parade and
the unicorn costume would be wasted.
That was kind of a bummer, but okay.
Anyway, the first thing that happened when I got to her party was that
Savannah greeted me at the door and asked: “Where’s your boyfriend, Summer?” I
didn’t even know what she was talking about. “I guess he doesn’t have to wear a
mask at Halloween, right?” she added. And then I knew she was talking about August.
“He’s not my boyfriend,” I said. “I know. I’m
just kidding!” She kissed my Che cheek (all the girls in her group kissed each
other’s cheeks now whenever they said hello), and threw my jacket on a coat rack
in her hallway. Then she took me by the hand down the stairs to her basement,
which is where the party was. I didn’t see her parents
anywhere. There were about 15 kids there: all of them were popular kids from
either Savannah's group or Julian’s group. I guess they’ve all kind of merged
into one big super group of popular kids, now that some of them have started
dating each other. I didn’t even know there were so many couples. I mean, I knew
about Savannah and Henry, but zamina and Miles? And Ellie and Amos? Ellie’s
practically as flat as I am. Anyway, about 5 minutes after I got there, Henry and
Savannah were standing next to me, literally hovering over me. “So, we went to
know why you hang out with the Zombie Kid so much,” said Henry. “He’s not a zombie
zie I laughed, like they were making a joke. I was smiling but I didn’t feel
like smiling. “You know, Summer,” said Savannah you would be a lot more popular
if you didn’t hang out with him so much.
I’m going to be completely honest with you: Julian likes you. He wants to ask you
out.” “He does?” “Do you think he’s cute?” “Um yeah, I guess. Yeah, he’s
cute.” “So you have to choose who you want to hang out with Savannah said. She was
talking to me like a big sister would talk to a little sister. “Everyone likes
you, Summer. Everyone thinks you’re really nice and that you’re really, really
pretty. You could totally be a part of our group if you wanted to, and believe
me, there are a lot of girls in our grade who would love that.” “I know.” I nodded.
“Thank you.” “You’re welcome,” she answered.
“You want me to tell Julian to come come and talk to you?” I looked over to where
she was pointing and could see Julian looking over at us. “Um, I actually need to
go to the bathroom. Where is that?” I went to where she pointed, sat down on the
side of the bathtub, and called Mom and asked her to pick me up. “Is everything
okay?” said Mom. “Yeah, I just don’t want to
stay,” I said. Mom didn’t ask any more questions and said she’d be there in 10
minutes. “Don’t ring the bell,” I told her.
“Just call me when you’re outside.” I hung out in the bathroom until Mom called, and
then I snuck upstairs without anyone seeing me, got my jacket, and went
outside. It was only 9:30 The Halloween Parade was in full swing down amford
Avenue. Huge crowds everywhere. Everyone was in costume. Skeletons. Pirates.
Princesses. Vampires.
Superheroes. But not one unicorn November THE NEXT DAY at school I told
Savannah I had eaten some really bad Halloween candy and gotten sick, which is
why I went home early from her party, and she believed me. There was actually a
stomach bug going around, so it was a good lie. I also told her that I had a
crush on someone else that wasn’t Julian so she would leave me alone about that
and hopefully spread the word to Julian that I wasn’t interested. She, of course,
wanted to to know who I had a crush on, and I told her it was a
secret. August was absent the day after Halloween, and when he came back, I could
tell something was up with him. He was acting so weird at lunch! He barely said
a word, and kept looking down at his food when I talked to him. Like he wouldn’t
look me in the eye. Finally, I was like, “Auggie, is
everything okay? Are you mad at me or something no No,” he said. “Sorry you
weren’t feeling well on Halloween. I kept looking for Boba Fett in the hallways.”
“Yeah, I was sick.” “Did you have that stomach bug?” “Yeah, I guess.” He opened a
book and started to read, which was kind of rude. “I’m so excited about the
Egyptian Museum project,” I said. “Aren’t you?” He shook his head, his mouth full of
food. I actually looked away because between the way he was chewing, which
almost seemed like he was being gross on purpose, and the way his eyes were just
kind of closed down, I was getting a really bad vibe from him. “What project
did you get?” I asked. He shrugged, pulled out a little scrap of paper from his
jeans pocket, and flicked it across the table to me. Everyone in the grade got
assigned an Egyptian artifact to work on for Egyptian Museum Day, which was in
December. The teachers wrote all the assignments down on tiny scraps of paper,
which they put into a fish bowl and then all us kids in the grade took turns
picking the papers out of the fish bowl in assembly. So I unfolded Auggie’s
little slip of paper. “Oh, cool!” I said, maybe a little over excited because I
was trying to get him psyched up. “You got the Step Pyramid of
Sakara I know!” he said. “I got anubus the god of the afterlife.” “The one with the
dog head?” “It’s actually a jackal head,” I corrected
him. “Hey, you want to start working on our projects together after school? You could
come over to my house.” He put his sandwich down and leaned back in his
chair. I can’t even describe the look he was giving me. “You know, Summer,” he said.
“You don’t have to do this.” “What are you talking about?” “You don’t have to be
friends with me. I know Mr. Tushman talked to you.” “I have no idea what you’re
talking about about You don’t have to pretend, is all I’m saying. I know Mr.
Tushman talked to some kids before school started and told them they had to
be friends with me.” “He did not talk to me,
August.” “Yeah, he did.” “No, he didn't Yeah, he
did.” “No he didn’t!! I swear on my life!” I
put my hands up in the air so he could see I wasn’t crossing my fingers. He
immediately looked down at my feet, so I shook off my ug so he could see my toes
weren’t crossed. “You’re wearing tights,” he said accusingly. “You can see my toes are
flat!” I yelled. “Okay, you don’t have to scream.” “I don’t like being accused of
things, okay?” “Okay. I’m sorry.” “You should be.”
“He really didn’t talk to you?” “Auggie!” “Okay, okay, I’m really sorry.” I would have
stayed mad at him longer, but then he told me about something bad that had
happened to him on Halloween and I couldn’t stay mad at him anymore.
Basically, he heard Jack badmouthing him and saying some really horrible things
behind his back. It kind of explained his attitude, and now I knew why he’d been out
“sick.” “Promise you won’t tell anyone,” he said. “I won’t.” I noded Promise you won’t
ever be mean like that to me again?” “Promise,” he said said and we pinky
swore warning this kid is rated R I HAD WARNED Mom about August’s face. I had
described what he' looked like. I did this because I know she’s not always so
good at faking her feelings, and August was coming over for the first time today.
I even sent her a text at work to remind
her about it. But I could tell from the expression on her face when she came
home after work that I hadn’t prepared her enough.
She was shocked when she came through the door and saw his face for the first
time. “Hi, Mom, this is Auggie. Can he stay for dinner?” I asked quickly. It took a
second for my mother to even register. “Hi Augie she said. “Um, of course,
sweetheart. If it’s okay with Auggie’s mother.” While Auggie called his mother on
his cell phone, I whispered to Mom: “Stop making that weirded out face!” She had
that look like when she’s watching the news and some horrific event has
happened. She nodded quickly, like she hadn’t realized she was making a face,
and was really nice and normal to Auggie afterward. After a while, Auggie and I got
tired of working on our projects and went to hang out in the living room.
Auggie was looking at the pictures on the mantle and he saw a picture of me
and Daddy. “Is that your dad?” he said. “Yeah.”
“I didn’t know you were what’s the word?” “Biracial.” “Right! That’s the word.” “Yeah.” He
looked at the picture again. “Are your parents divorced? I’ve never seen him at
drop off or anything.” “Oh, no,” I said. “He was a platoon sergeant. He died a few years
ago oh I didn’t know that.” “Yeah.” I nodded,
handing him a picture of my dad in his uniform. “Wow, look at all those medals.”
“Yeah. He was pretty awesome.” “Wow, Summer.
I’m sorry.” “Yeah, it sucks. I really miss him a
lot.” “Yeah, wow.” He nodded, handing me back the picture. “Have you ever known anyone
who died?” I asked. “Just my grandmother, and I don’t really even remember her.” “That’s
too bad.” Auggie nodded. “You ever wonder what happens to
people when they die?” I asked. He shrugged.
“Not really. I mean, I guess they go to heaven? That’s where my Grands went.” “I
think about it a lot,” I said. “I think when people die, their souls go to heaven but
just for a little while. Like that’s where they see their old friends and
stuff, and kind of catch up on old times.
But then I actually think the souls start thinking about their lives on
earth, like if they were good or bad or whatever. And then they get born again as
brand new babies in the world.” “Why would they want to do that?”
“Because then they get another chance to get it right,” I answered. “Their souls get
a chance to have a doover He thought about what I was saying and then nodded.
“Kind of like when you get a makeup test,” he said. “Right.” “But they don’t come back
looking the same,” he said. “I mean, they look completely different when they come back, right?”
“Oh yeah,” I answered. “Your soul stays the same but everything else is different.” “I
like that,” he said, nodding a lot. “I really like that, Summer. That means in my next
life I won’t be stuck with this face.” He pointed to his face when he said that
and battered his eyes, which made me laugh. “I guess not.” I shrugged. “Hey, I might
even be handsome!” he said, smiling. “That would be so awesome, wouldn’t it? I could
come back and be this goodlooking dude and be super buff and super tall.” I
laughed again. He was such a good sport about himself. That’s one of the things I
like the most about Auggie. “Hey, Auggie, can I ask you a question?” “Yeah,” he said,
like he knew exactly what I wanted to ask. I hesitated. I’ve been wanting to ask
him this for a while but I’ve always lost the guts to ask. “What?” he said. “You
want to know what’s wrong with my
face?” “Yeah, I guess. If it’s okay for me to
ask.” He shrugged. I was so relieved that he didn’t seem mad or
sad. “Yeah, it’s no big deal,” he said casually. “The main thing I have is this
thing called mandolo facial DSis which took me forever to learn how
to pronounce, by the way. But I also have this other syndrome thing that I can’t
even pronounce. And these things kind of just morph together into one big super
thing which is so rare they don’t even
have a name for it. I mean, I don’t want
to brag or anything, but I’m actually considered something of a medical wonder, you know.” He
smiled. “That was a joke,” he said. “You can laugh.” I smiled and shook my head. “You’re
funny Augie I said. “Yes, I am,” he said proudly. “I am cool
beans the Egyptian tomb OVER THE NEXT month, August and I hung out a lot after
school, either at his house or my house.
August’s parents even invited Mom and me over for dinner a couple of times. I
overheard them talking about fixing Mom up on a blind date with August’s uncle
Ben. On the day of the Egyptian Museum exhibit, we were all really excited and kind of giddy.
It had snowed the day before— —not as much as it had snowed over the Thanksgiving
break, but still, snow is snow. The gym was turned into a giant museum, with
everyone’s Egyptian artifact displayed on a table with a little caption card
explaining what the thing was. Most of the artifacts were really great, but I
have to say I really think mine and August’s were the best. My sculpture of
Anubis looked pretty real, and I had even used real gold paint on it in August had
made his step pyramid out of sugar cubes.
It was 2 ft high and 2 ft long, and he had spray painted the cubes with this
kind of fake sand paint or something. It looks so awesome. We all dressed up in
Egyptian costumes. Some of the kids were Indiana Jones– –type
archaeologist Some of them dressed up like pharaohs. August and I dressed up
like mummies. Our faces were covered except for two little holes for the eyes
and one little hole for the mouth. When the parents showed up, they all lined up
in the hallway in front of the gym. Then we were told we could go get our parents
each kid got to take his or her parent on a flashlight tour through the dark
gym. August and I took our moms around together. We stopped at each exhibit,
explaining what it was, talking in whispers, answering questions. Since it
was dark, we used our flashlights to illuminate the artifacts while we were
talking. Sometimes, for dramatic effect, we would hold the Flash Lights under our
chins while we were explaining something in detail. It was so much fun, hearing all
these whispers in the dark, seeing all the lights zigzagging around the dark
room. At one point, I went over to get a drink at the water fountain. I had to
take the mummy wrap off my face. “Hey, Summer,” said Jack, who came over
to talk to me. He was dressed like the man from The Mummy “Cool costume.” “Thanks.”
“Is the other mummy August?” “Yeah.” “Um hey, do you know why August is
mad at me uhhuh I nodded. “Can you tell me?”
“No.” He nodded. He seemed bum I told him I
wouldn’t tell you,” I explained. “It’s so
weird,” he said. “I have no idea why he’s
mad at me all of a sudden. None. Can’t you
at least give me a hint?” I looked over at where August was across the room, talking
to our moms. I wasn’t about to break my solid oath that I wouldn’t tell anyone
about what he overheard at Halloween, but I felt bad for Jack. “Bleeding
Scream,” I whispered in his ear, and then walked away thank you so much for watching
please remember to Like And subscribe become a channel member and we'll see you next time